Josuke, I'm going hunting.
Huh?
And I want you to come along.
Hang on, slow down.
Did you say "hunting"?
You don't mean…
we're goin' huntin' for
hotties with nice bodies?
I'm more the romantic type,
so you'll have to show
this newbie the ropes.
I don't know
if I can pull it off…
Akira Otoishi came clean
about his past yesterday.
He did?!
Seems there was a lot we didn't
know about his bow and arrow use.
Turns out he also
shot a rat with the arrow.
A rat?!
But the rat didn't die.
Writhing in agony, it managed
to free itself from the arrow
and headed for the hills.
In other words, it may be a rat,
but it undoubtedly
acquired Stand abilities.
What it can do, I have no idea.
We have to hunt it down
before it can cause any harm.
JOJO'S BIZARRE ADVENTURE
DIAMOND IS UNBREAKABLE
A demon's crept into
our everyday life
It's about to take away
something precious
Our peace has already
crumbled long ago
So casually, so nonchalantly
It's taken from us
before we know it
If we want it back,
now's the chance
With the sharpness of
the piercing arrow
The beauty of two souls united
Wherever you go, chase you
Whenever, chase you
I will chase you
Nowhere to escape
Start running, I will chase you
Tomorrow, chase you
My fists will be the one
to show you
Tenacity decides
who will win or lose
So I chase you
EPISODE 16
LET'S GO HUNTING!
Wow, super kewl!
Keeping a nimble rat
within range won't be easy,
but shooting these bearings
will expand it to about 20 meters.
And of course,
they're useless against Stands.
Use them for downing the user.
Give it a try.
I have to use 'em, too?
I don't know…
I don't have the concentration
for ball sports and stuff.
I almost got the second one!
Not bad. I'd give you an 85.
Before we begin our hunt,
you have to remember one thing:
When dealing with live animals,
you have to place
composure over speed.
If you find the rat
within range and miss,
don't expect it
to come within range again.
So hold your fire until you're
positive you can hit your target.
No pressure though.
Got it?
He sure knows how
to make a guy feel at ease.
Seems Akira Otoishi shot the rat
near this irrigation canal.
Given the location, it was probably
the common Brown Rat.
Brown Rats are agile swimmers,
highly adaptable,
and can eat practically anything.
Larger rats can grow up to
20 - 30 centimeters long.
And some can weigh
as much as one kilogram.
Their horizontal leap
is about 2 meters.
Found it.
Aren't those bird tracks?
Its forefeet have four digits,
its hindfeet have five.
It's making this S-shape
because it's dragging something.
These markings are tail tracks.
The rat must be
about 20 centimeters long.
I can't tell how many,
but we've definitely got a rat.
There's a tick on this leaf.
This is a stomping ground for rats.
There's no question,
somewhere in that drain is a nest.
For now, we'll set a trap and
see what the video camera picks up.
That's one of those cameras
that lets you watch
while you're recording, right?
You're not gonna use cheese?
It's a hunk of tempura.
Cheese is too luxurious for a rat.
What's with all these flies…
Jotaro!
Th-These are…
Dead rats?
Yeah, no shit!
It looks like a block
of jellied fish.
Why are you poking it?!
It's flesh.
At some point,
the flesh of these rats
melted and later congealed.
Something melted their flesh
subcutaneously, killing them.
How does that even happen?
I don't have the answer…
Safe to say it's the doing
of that rat we're after.
You think it used a Stand to…
It exterminated its fellow rats
to dominate the territory.
Which means…
It's highly likely the rat's making
a nest in that drain.
The question is,
has whatever's done this
done anything else?
Looks like the drainage canal
continues on to that house.
We might already be too late.
R-Really?
I see a chicken coop,
but no chickens.
And no sign of activity
in that house, either.
Their cars are still parked
in the garage,
and the front door isn't locked.
The rat must be there.
It doesn't look good.
The inhabitants of this house
have likely already been killed.
Come on, we have to investigate.
The rat will let us
approach up to a point.
It knows most humans
are too slow to ever catch it.
It's not expecting us
to use it as target practice.
That's how we'll close in
and put it down with one shot.
Bingo.
Rat droppings.
No grass or grain here.
It's meat.
The droppings continue
into this room.
Let's look.
Right.
What is that?
A refrigerator compressor?
What the heck?
Did this refrigerator
open its own door?
Did the door's magnet give out?
Shit! There it is!
Holy shit! It's right there!
So that's what opened the door!
Rats can open refrigerator doors?!
No way… Someone must've
forgotten to shut the door.
Come on, are you really
that gullible, Josuke?
This rat's a Stand user!
Jo—
Jotaro's gone!
He went into the next room.
Great. Our eyes've met.
Th-This is…
The rat did this?!
They're still alive…
Did that rat disfigure the people
of this house with its Stand
to then store them in the fridge?
And it's eating them!
Damn it…
Jotaro's not coming back.
I'm gonna have to kill this thing.
When dealing with live animals,
it's composure above speed.
If I don't knock him off on
my first try, he'll know my range.
That's what he said Shit…
He sure can lay on the pressure!
Of course,
the table and chair are positioned
just enough to be in my way
I gotta make sure I sink
this ball bearing
right between his eyes.
Now stay right there…
Crap! He stopped eating.
If I move any more,
he'll run for it!
Fudge it! It'll be an adventure.
I'll blast him from right here!
He's moving! Now!
CRUSH
Yes!
It didn't kill him!
He's come out!
That must be his Stand!
You wanna take me on, huh?
I'd watch out if I were you!
My next shot will
knock you out for good!
Dammit!
He's running under the table!
No, you don't!
Jotaro, what the hell
are you doing over there?!
The rat's here!
That shape…
Uh-oh! Its Stand shoots!
Now what? Slap it away
with my bare hands?
On second thought,
that's kinda gross…
Which is it?
Did I hit it, or did I miss?
Little bastard!
Yeah! I got him!
It wasn't his forehead,
but he's a goner.
That was close…
Jotaro, over here!
I got the rat! It's over!
Jeez. What were you doing?
You went missing right
when I needed ya.
I got lonely back there.
Well, it's the funniest thing…
Lucky for me,
that shot didn't go balls up.
For me, at least.
His Stand shot
some needle-like things at me.
I bet those are what
turn your flesh to goo.
He got the people in this house,
but they're still alive.
I'll fix 'em right up
with Shining Diamond.
If we don't hunt him down
by sundown,
things might get even messier.
Huh?
That wasn't the only rat.
Another one got me.
Jotaro! Y-Your hand…
It happened in the room over there.
I could have dodged it…
Catching its needle for analysis
wasn't the best choice.
All it takes is a touch,
and its Stand's poison begins
to permeate, melting even Stands.
Five or six hits,
and you'll turn into
a quivering mass of flesh.
Thank god that thing didn't hit me!
Who knew my personality
would come in handy.
The rat ran outside
after he hit me.
It must've figured out you killed
its relative in the kitchen.
Sorry to bother,
but I'm sort of counting on
your curative powers here.
O-Oh, right!
Damn it!
Why'd those little S.O.B.s
have to multiply?
STAR PLATINUM
Hello, this is the Speedwagon
Foundation research department.
Hello, this is Jotaro Kujo.
Jotaro!
We've tried to reach you
several times.
I was hunting and
turned the ringer off.
This isn't about Otoishi, is it?
Yes. Akira Otoishi was covering up
his shooting of two rats.
Got it.
Two, not three or four, right?
Yes, we're certain of it.
Good grief, Akira Otoishi…
Way to go.
When it comes to its own territory,
it will kill everything,
humans and rats alike.
It cares only about itself.
It's time its life on earth
comes to an end.
Jotaro, wait!
A teeny-weeny rat just
ran into an open field…
How exactly do you plan
on tracking this thing down?
Ernest Thompson Seton famously said
there is no animal
that cannot be tracked.
Rats are known to
avoid unfamiliar paths.
Which means, its route of escape
had to be that irrigation channel.
And there's something else
about rats…
Without the constant
intake of food,
within hours,
they'll starve to death.
There…
Those are fresh bite marks.
Yes! This is awesome!
We'll corner
that little buck-toothed bastard!
Take a look at this.
I don't think it even
looked at our bait.
We got him on tape.
Its ear looks like
a bug-eaten leaf.
This little guy is "Bug-Eaten."
Look how careful he's being…
Unlike earlier, Bug-Eaten
is going to be extra careful to
not let us within 20 meters of him.
These are live rifle rounds.
Worst case, we've got these to use.
L-Live rounds?!
Due to drag, ball bearings lose
a great deal of accuracy
when traveling over 20 meters.
With a bullet nose like this,
we'll be okay up to 70 meters.
Am I going to have to launch that
with my Stand's hand, too?
I don't think I'm ready for that.
Apparently not.
Then it'll have to be me.
Hold it right there…
What do you mean by that?
That really pissed me off.
Remember, I'm the one
who nailed that other one!
Sure, it wasn't exactly perfect,
but…
Guess you're right.
You get two then.
Huh?
More pressure…
Careful. This puddle's got leeches.
What?!
Shit…
What now?
Careful, Josuke.
The footprints suddenly stop here.
What is this?!
Why would they suddenly stop?
I know! It must be underground.
It must've burrowed
a hole and covered itself.
No!
It's called backtracking…
I didn't expect rats
to be capable of this, too.
Backtracking?
Backtracking is the way in which
a wild animal will reverse itself
by stepping in its own tracks
to hide from predators.
In Japan, the behavior
has been observed
with brown bears,
weasels, and rabbits.
But never with any species of rat.
So basically, what that means is…
the rat pulled a fast one on us.
Looks like things've
taken a turn for the worse.
With this kind of terrain…
we may've just gone
from hunters to prey.
I have this creepy feeling
we're being watched.
I think we better hide
behind a rock.
No sudden movements…
Bug-Eaten's attack
isn't too fast for us to see.
Keep an eye out
for the point of fire.
If we can find where it's hiding,
we'll snipe it instead.
What the hell?!
Wha—?!
That dirty rodent used
the rat trap on us?
Star Platinum, The World!
Good grief.
Don't worry.
I removed the needle
before the poison spread,
along with the affected tissue.
Put a bandage on it.
I also located
his general whereabouts.
Halfway up the hill,
near those three rocks.
Amazing! You and that rat!
Guess the only chump now is me…
It's 60 meters away.
I see no sign of another
needle launch.
It knows random fire will
give away its precise location,
and open itself up to attack.
Stubborn bastard.
Why are you praising that damn rat?
We need to act.
Well said, Josuke.
We need to give this
everything we've got,
or Bug-Eaten's gonna
take us both out.
I'll give you all four rounds.
At this distance,
it'll rise like a slider,
so aim one centimeter
below the target.
Jotaro? What are you going to do?
I'm moving in
so he'll shoot his needles.
You, Josuke, are going to
determine his location…
Then you're going to shoot him.
W-What?!
You don't have a choice.
Even if one or two
of his needles get me,
Shining Diamond can heal me.
Remember, Josuke,
you can't heal yourself.
It's balls to the wall, Josuke!
Could I have a second
to mentally prepare?
Star Platinum, The World!
Find him?
N-No…
As soon as he fired, he moved!
I'll try to get closer while
going up the side of the hill.
Watch for the moment he fires.
The moment he fires…
Damn this pressure!
There! I see him!
What?!
That bastard predicted I'd dodge,
then fired the needles
at the rocks?
They ricocheted?
Jotaro!
Quit staring at me, Josuke!
Keep your eye on the rat!
The moment he attacks,
obliterate him!
This isn't good
I've got four rounds,
but no more chances.
If I waste any time…
Here we go, Josuke.
There! Same spot as before.
But he's hiding behind the rocks.
Shit! If only he was
looking over here…
I've gotta do this!
I'll just have to hit
a tiny target!
I suddenly feel
that fighting spirit.
I'm gonna get you, little fucker.
Josuke missed…
So you did look.
I thought my miss
would make you look
and turn your body toward me.
Soon I'll have you
right in my crosshairs.
So I guess I wasn't a chump,
after all.
Call me Josuke Higashikata,
vanquisher of pressure and stress!
Akira Otoishi's
mutant Stand rats…
calls to mind our own destruction
of the environment…
Not exactly sure
how I should feel…
At least Josuke's a dependable guy.
Good grief.
Maybe this means
a little peace of mind.
EPISODE 17
ROHAN KISHIBE'S ADVENTURE